[Music]
all arguing with each other who's got
his rest whose religion is best let's
just put all of that stuff to one side
for it easy to disagree about thing left
instead try and find some common ground
something that we can unite behind I'm
I'm here trying to talk about inequality
that exists in our society some of the
reasons why in equality is growing and
some of the things we might do to try
and take some of the power back but it's
been stripped away from it oh the world
and it runs right now is not sustainable
it is not equitable and it is not
sensible our financial system runs on
debt money is produced only in response
to the need for low God's match that
money then requires the payment of
insurance but the money to pay the
interest is never created that there is
constantly a shortfall in our financial
system default bankruptcies are an
inevitable consequence of it our
political system is producing ever more
divisive and extreme leaders look at
Trump look at lepen look at the rise of
the far-right throughout Europe this is
going on right now and it's getting
worse our media spreads lie it spreads
fear it spreads messages of division and
distrust threatening us against each
other
barring us from collaborating with each
other and actually solving like some of
the real problem that exists here right
now consumerism and credit have run
completely out of control in order to
keep getting cheap goods on ourselves we
are exploiting workers in poor countries
such wondrous young ascore working with
less than a dollar a day remind COBOL so
we can have mobile phones we live it up
here in the Western world while poor
people all over the place are being
essentially murdered through slave labor
even here in rich countries our
prisoners are paid as little as 30 cents
a day to assemble good so that we can
have cheap stuff on our shelves as long
as
keep trying only good we don't ask too
many questions about our masters that
was actually going on in the world after
system is dysfunctional in dozens and
dozens of ways not to mention
unbelievably wasteful
here's an excellent example there are 32
million cards currently registered in
the UK all those 32 million cards
anything between 80 and 99% of them at
any given moment are inactive set set
perhaps on the side of the road
somewhere not being used not serving
anyone locking two lanes that could
potentially be used for the flow of
traffic all of that metal all of that
rubber all of that glass justice that
they're not doing anything in a sensible
world we would have come up by now with
some kind of co-ownership schemes some
kind of sharing of these resources
rather than having them sit there
inactive our energy it's still primal
our electricity rather it's still
primarily produced by the burning of
fossil fuel the battery believe it or
not was invented back in 1800 the
hydrogen fuel cell 1839 solar panel 1954
windmills portables a bit around for
centuries there's two your thermal which
hasn't even been begun to be exploited
yet tidal power hasn't even begun to be
exploited yet why is research not going
into these things because more money for
oil companies money telling us and ever
and ever going to fly of oil the car
thing why do we not have driverless
water making electric cars on the road
ready technology did with the reason is
very simple
changing tires refueling car financing
the purchase of new cars on debt and
servicing mo T's Rotax all of these
things are revenue streams for
corporations and government the planet
is entirely coercive we do not get a
choice in this we pay our taxes
I'm on salary before you can get our
money one of our Tech's project I'll
keep bailing out banks refurbishing our
Trident missile system building
pointless hs2 job sorry I've lost my
thread I just need to fertilize forgive
me I'm new to this I'm still I'm still
learning the wrong way wrong way sorry
sorry boy I will get oh yeah oh yeah so
our farmers in its enriched comes got
paid to massively overview certain crops
and then paid again believe it or not to
destroy those from all of that surplus
food production is more than enough to
feed all the starving of the world right
now
today our pharmaceutical company making
hundreds of billions in profits every
year and yet one only I could not
believe this that when I read it and yet
100 thousand people die every single day
on this planet wonders and children's
use of poverty and preventable disease
in a sensible world that kind of shit
just could not happen you know well when
a job is automated when i--when a robot
is it takes over the job what happens
people get laid off they don't get wages
anymore they can't support themselves
they can't feed their family in a
cylindrical world just one minute and
then I'll gladly take questions that's
right in a sensible world automation of
a child boring repetitive dangerous jobs
no I'm all right I think I can be heard
but thank you an automation of a job
like that which should be cause for
celebration right because people don't
able to do it anymore
more time to learn without family
hearing more time to spend on leisure
money because in the book it wasn't
recorded oh no oh I see in that case not
at all I talking about as an amplifier
absolutely no no I'm very respectable
non-hearing where was I where well oh
yes so together in a sensible world
automation photography abroad it doesn't
celebrate because it means less shitty
work for people to do our educational
system
deliberately Sadam the children down so
that they can't political thinkers
it makes fertile soil for the mix to be
planted by our news agencies by our
media file propagandist by an
advertising company by our marketing
purposes oh yeah thank you in a sensible
world young people will be educated to
be free thinkers to challenge the state
of violence prevalence free to come up
with imaginative solutions to problems
rather than Northup the scripted
curriculum learn these parts pouring old
back the you look up on the Internet
anyway and then we will assess you on
your ability to regurgitate those back
and if you do a good job we'll give you
an a what the fuck is that all about the
fact is that we do not live in a
sensible world in our world children can
very much more about outcomes than they
do about earning they can clearly
compare much more about the image than
they do about their character more about
popularity with about integrity more
about blame than about responsibility
this the direction it's not their fault
this is a direct reflection of the
society in which they are growing up
yeah our values have been twisted and
corrupted in our world people between
more time with it both than they do with
their friends spend more money on
servicing in depth than they do on
servicing their families you know we'll
get this it's another unbelievable set
in our world 70% of arable land is used
to grow food lots of people the cows and
in the meantime
government paid subs people company to
the top down rainforests needs to make
room for grazing for cows and then those
cows because that is shitty grazing land
those cow has been fed on the grain
which is then imported over thousands of
miles we promote animals then what
happens the excess because roundup fed
back to the cows again and this is where
the SE came from this is insanity it is
madness
and this is the way we run our society
son the final questions I select must be
already wondering alright fine yeah
great I agree with you these are all big
problems what can we do about the right
becomes the next question and this is
the hardest of all of the questions
because the fact is change is not going
to come from the top down
that's your 300 million P and I don't
mean God I mean our governments and
corporations and banks it is not in
their interests to try and change
anything because they're already doing
very nicely thank you very much but
bottom three or four billion people on
this planet are doing everything they
can from day to day just to survive so
it's up to us it's up to us the middle
class and the working people in rich
country is up to us to find solutions to
these problems where are we going to
find in solution well technology by
increasing technology and by breaking
human ingenuity and trusting that these
things can solve all of our problems for
us but we can't rely on government under
it we cover our corporations if they
have their own agendas of making money
sucking our labor sucking our creativity
for their own ends there we go
can you elaborate more on how do you
mean by we embraced a question about
alternative fuel source I'm talking
about in every way to alternative fuel
sources but what I'm talking about is
people coming up with local solutions to
local problems not relying on
governments to sort their stuff out
border but empowering themselves and
they committed me as certain things app
themselves and we have one thing now
because you know what rich people a bit
exploiting poor people for thousands of
years which is nothing new right but
what's different between now and any
climate history is the internet for the
first time ever we have the power to
communicate on a global scale and so one
community comes up as a solution to a
problem
they can immediately communicate that
solution everywhere else other people
can take that solution adapt it refine
it for their own needs and by sharing in
an open-source way by communicating
forming networks and relationships with
other people and with other communities
we can start finding our own solutions
for education our own
the things that we think are going to be
a value to them in later life start
coming up with our own way to sorting
and purifying water start coming up with
our own ways of generating energy and
growing food you know get out get our
basic vital needs covered by ourselves
and then we can start ignoring the
operates essential control apparatus and
in time hopefully this is my dream in
time and community become more powerful
more independent more connected to each
other that sense of control systems of
government and finance and politics and
legal systems will become irrelevant
outmoded outdated obsolete they are no
longer needed they are no longer fit and
purposes we can sort our own lives out I
read a really interesting book recently
talking about chaos theory as it relates
to as it relates to social structures
chaos theory is about complex systems
lots and lots of individual part all
doing their own things that connected
and are part of a larger system chaotic
systems naturally automatically find
ways of self-organizing and this is what
we have to trust that our society or
service we do not need pencil our
structures tell us what to do we do not
need central power structures to tell us
what is right and wrong we know in our
own heart in our own conscience what is
right and wrong we do not need laws and
government facilities things we need to
trap in our creativity in our ingenuity
and in our ability to make tools to do
the jobs that we need to do and then as
I say the centralized power structure
that currently exists will crumble away
they will simply fade away into
non-existence and we can then I hope
build something new and more resembling
an actual human society and out of the
rubble character what's your opinions
and freedom of speech
is an absolute as far as I'm concerned
anyone should be able to say anything
they want and if you don't want to
listen to it they can walk away do you
know what I mean they say it does if
they don't agreement if they find it
hateful or hurtful or whatever just walk
away you don't need to punch the guy
right now you don't need to shoot the
guy just cause you could agree with him
that's right so yeah freedom of speech
should be absolute in my opinion fixes
but please please engage me in
conversation action bury my throat is
getting a little bit soft but I also
have lots of little things here to hand
out some website addresses where you can
maybe learn a little bit more people if
you're interested things now where we
always get a certain amount of money or
something value that is one I mean under
the existing system that is one way of
really bored is the universal analysis
yeah how it makes the pressures away
yeah yeah yeah we're planning it now and
it's up anyway so somebody gave me 17 I
forgot what it was about whatever look
at it sometime spray for babies right
Finland they're trying it's not linear
tiling it and in I think Kenya I think I
could be wrong about it so definitely
somewhere in appetite I think Kenya I
think Kenya VA it is being trialed and I
mean the fact is that more and more and
more job will be automated over the
coming decades right and we're going to
have hundreds of millions people with no
job to do anymore so what are they going
to do you know I think one of them one
of the myths is propagated to keep it
separate and to keep us not challenging
Authority is that without a controlling
Authority people are lazy and self is
going to sit around scratching in office
no one will contribute I don't believe
that I believe human nation be more
positive than that and the human nature
has been corrupted and perverted by our
social constructs
please take anyone anyone takes my
throat is very very sore I'm running out
running out of steam here but if anyone
wants to ask anything we'll make the
point I'm really happy we really have to
do this to be interactive I don't want
it always be lecturing you know what I
mean no so what would you say how do we
get to the situation wind right now oh
it's happened over a very long time like
I said I mean go back as far as the
Egyptians that's what port right there
he is and gentlemen is it is captain ISM
what so he says what captain ago well I
would have thought capitalism would come
up at some point cleaners we're Tyria
you're probably upwards on twelve
depends of what what subject we're
talking about
if the information capitalism expensive
with the central government it's a
problem I mean our for example for
example what is universal credit what
are universal credit for benefit it's a
benefit which is paid to people who
don't getting up on a job try to chop it
up right away so they can punch you can
be olive oil get in a bedroom look at a
slightly different way what it actually
is is a government subsidy to
corporations to under pay their workers
right only in the case of those who are
working it also goes to Hitler don't
don't work also guys out were absolutely
right absolutely right one there the
bigger number
not the people on tartlet learn on top
I'm not sure that - but I don't have a
number to hand I don't know and I don't
know if I'll cook my head but you know
there's been a lot in the papers over
the last couple of years about big
corporations not being their fair share
attack their argument being that well
our employees will pay income tax we pay
the 80 on all of our purchases etc
everyone agrees on argument films I
think everyone agrees that our that
argument fish so the parliamentary
committees of the blood interests of all
Google uber Facebook eBay and write the
question now is buying into my standing
to make that work
there's a one country starts typing in
corporation they'll move very simply to
make each corporation pays don't act any
cutter then recovered or not means you
need a company one place worked and that
was because Walmart which got me
something closed acted on the country's
this the structure of their economy